Hello everyone and welcome to English Pod.
My name is Marko.
My name is Catherine
and today we have an
advanced level lesson for
you guys all about food.
What kind of food are we
talking about today Marko?
Today we're talking
about cheese. So there's so
many different types of
cheese, so many varieties.
So we're going to take
a look at these varieties.
You may know them
or not, but we're also
going to take a look at
the pronunciation because
most of them are
either Italian or French.
So how do you pronounce these
in maybe in American English?
Good question. Let's
listen to our dialogue for
the first time and we'll
be back in a moment
to talk about the
wonderful world of cheese.
Hello everyone. My name is Lori and
I want to welcome you to this course.
We will learn all about
one of the oldest yet
most delicious foods
on this planet, cheese.
Let's get started.
Cheese is usually
categorized into four types.
Soft, semi soft, semi hard, and hard.
The designation refers
to the amount of moisture
in the cheese, which
directly affects its texture.
Making cheese is an ancient practice
dating back thousands of years.
And the home cheese
maker can usually find recipes
for cheese that fall into
any of the four categories.
Soft cheese includes
cottage cheese, cream cheese,
ricotta, brie, blue, ricquefore,
mozzarella, minster, and similar cheeses.
These cheeses generally
pair well with fruits
or meats and can be used as breakfast
cheeses in an omelet or as pasta fillings.
They are usually mildly flavored
and very high in moisture.
American, Colby, Co-Jack, and similar
cheeses are in the semi soft category.
These are slightly stronger in
flavor and cover a wide range of uses.
Co-Jack cheese, a blend of Colby and
Monterey Jack, is one of the most popular.
This allows the sharper flavor
of the Colby to be combined with
the milder Jack cheese and
also melts better than plain Colby.
Grilled cheese sandwiches often
use American cheese and Mexican
cheeses such as Asadero and
Gisofresco are becoming more popular.
Hard cheeses include Parmesan,
Romano, Asiago, Swiss, Gruyere, and others.
Parmesan and Romano are most familiar as
the grated powder used to top spaghetti but
they are also used as a companionments for
fruit, wine, nuts, and other appetizer items.
Swiss is a popular sandwich cheese and
melts well unlike some other hard cheeses.
Alright, we're back so obviously
this is a very interesting lesson
because it also gives us an insight
onto how cheeses are categorized.
I personally did not
know that you had all these
categories of cheeses starting
out with the soft cheeses.
That's right, so basically
they're broken into
these soft semi soft, semi
hard and hard categories.
The soft cheeses are
the ones that are actually,
you know, you could
touch them and they're soft.
They just kind of move under your finger.
And the famous ones I think are
cottage cheese which is almost like yogurt.
Yeah, and cream cheese, like
is all in cream cheese as well.
But also ricotta and brie
and ruck for and mozzarella.
So for example, these
cheeses, they're usually,
well they're obviously
very soft cheeses.
Do you say cheeses or
cheese, or cheese-eye?
Yeah, we just say cheese normally
or different kinds of cheese.
So in that case you make the plural
kinds of cheese, types of cheese.
So these kinds of cheese,
they are recommended or
they say that they pair
well with fruits or meat.
So when we talk about
pairing a cheese with fruits or
pairing a cheese with wine,
what are we saying there?
In that case we're saying that it's
best to eat with certain kinds of food.
And so you can say I would recommend
pairing this red wine with lamb.
But in the case of cheese
you could say I would
recommend pairing this
delicious brie cheese with fruit.
Okay, so you actually have brie with fruit.
That's right, well it depends
on the kind of cheese.
A lot of times you see
mozzarella on pizzas
and so it's not paired, it's
actually a part of the dish.
It's ingredient, right?
But if you're going to
eat a piece of cheese
alone, you can have it
maybe with some fruit.
So I guess that's the
main difference between
pairing and having it as
an ingredient is pairing
you're combining it but
it's not really part of the dish.
No and as an ingredient it's actually,
it has to be in the dish to make it work.
And so you have a lot
of these delicious soft
cheeses that you eat at breakfast or
sometimes dessert, ricotta, cream cheese.
These are all parts of desserts
like cheesecake for example.
Oh yeah, what did they use in cheesecake?
Usually cream cheese.
But then you get into
these other cheeses
which are semi soft or semi hard
and semi here just means part.
So it's partially hard, partially soft.
And these cheeses are
different because you might
use them sliced on
sandwiches, things like that.
In this category you
have American and Colby
and Monterey Jack is
also very, very popular.
So these actually do have
a more American sound
to it, obviously American
cheese or Monterey Jack.
That sounds a little bit
different than all the Italian
or French sounding cheeses
that we had in the soft ones.
That's right and you'd
even have something
like cheddar in this category,
there's another cheddar cheese.
Yeah, there's another cheese.
As you said, these are very
typically put in sandwiches.
Yeah, I mean you can
use them in different ways.
Because we grate cheese, that means we rub
it against this machine, a grater to make
it come out in these
little fine pieces, for
example, on top of
pasta or on top of nachos.
So we have grated cheese, but
you can also have sliced cheese
and that's the way that we cut
cheese to put it on a sandwich.
So for example, if you go to
McDonald's and you get a burger,
usually the cheese that's on your
hamburger is cheddar cheese, right?
That's right.
It's a slice of cheddar cheese.
Okay.
Now, moving on to
our next cadaver, we'll
actually towards the
end of the different types
of cheese under the semi-soft category.
They also talk about Mexican cheeses,
such as assa deiro and queso fresco.
I love queso fresco.
You've had this before.
Yes, many times.
What do you usually have
it with or how do you pair it?
Usually it's an ingredient on tacos because
it's a little bit crumbly that means that
it's like balls as opposed to
being one chunk, one big piece.
And so we usually have it like that or I've
also had it as a just a piece of cheese
paired with a fried plantain or sour cream.
Yeah.
It's actually very good.
The thing with queso fresco is
all of the cheese, they also depend
on how mature they are, how
long they've taken to make them.
And queso fresco means fresh in Spanish.
And this is the main factor
in this type of cheeses.
It is very, very immature.
It's a very fresh cheese you make.
You can make it in like a day or two.
Exactly.
It just takes one night to sit
and to become cheese basically.
But other cheeses, and
we'll see some of these
in the hard cheeses take a very long
time to become their final cheese state.
And one of those cheeses is Parmesan.
You know, in Italy, when
you buy Parmesan, they
have these big wheels
of it, their circles.
And you have to pay
according to how old it is.
Oh, really?
18 months, 36 months.
And it gets more expensive the older it is.
So obviously the older it is, just
like wine, it has a more intense flavor.
That's right.
And there are special
characteristics for certain ages.
Sometimes people
really like the young ones.
It depends on your taste and
what you're going to use it for.
But Romano is another cheese in Italy
that's used like Parmesan on top of pastas.
So spaghetti, you grate it
and you put it on top of pastas.
Okay.
What about that?
They also mentioned this other one, Asiago.
Asiago cheese, Swiss cheese
is the one with the holes.
Asiago is, I don't know
if maybe it's Spanish.
But then we have Gruyere,
which is a French cheese
and tends to be very,
very, very strong-flavored.
So I think Gruyere is the cheese that
usually many people use for making fondue.
So they basically
have this big pot or this
medium-sized pot and
all the cheese just melts
and you just dip pieces
of bread or vegetables
in there and you eat
this just melted cheese.
Fondue, very popular dish in Switzerland.
That's right.
But yeah, these are all these
different types of cheese.
As you said, there are so many
different types and according to the age.
Now you lived in
Italy for a while and
obviously they are a
very, they're a nation that
enjoy having wine and
cheese very regularly, right?
That's right.
And I have to say that people in part might
take their cheese very, very seriously.
How serious.
Well, a lot of people buy these big pieces
of Parmesan cheese and they keep them in
their refrigerator and you don't just
put the Parmesan cheese on the spaghetti.
You also break pieces
of it and you eat it
alone with some glass
of wine or some people
like to put a little drop
of balsamic vinegar
on top of the cheese
to give it some flavor.
Oh, really?
So there are many different ways to eat it.
I'm sure it's different
all over the country
but mozzarella,
Parmesan cheese, Romano.
These are all cheeses that are
very, very important in Italian culture.
It's very interesting because obviously we
have listeners from all over the world but
some countries have a good culture
for wine, cheese and cured meats.
For example, in South America, if you visit
Argentina or Chile, they are a nation that
actually have a lot of variety of
cheese, wines and cured meats.
But if you take a trip to maybe Colombia,
they're not really that type of culture.
They're really consume cheese
and wine in the same manner.
Interesting.
I wonder if it has to
do with the historical
relationship between Europe
and the place like Argentina.
Argentina, there's
lots of Italian former
people who came over from
Italy many, many years ago.
Right.
So that might have something to do with it.
Spain has a very strong tradition
of cured meats and cheeses.
They have macchago
cheese, things like this.
So I wonder if there's
a relationship there.
Yeah, I think it's definitely
an influence in some way.
But the thing with cheese, I think
it's in many places, it's very expensive.
It can be.
Comparatively too, you
know, if you can have a
regular mozzarella cheese
but sometimes these
other types, they
can be very expensive.
Yeah, it's like good wine.
If you really want to pay for good cheese,
it's going to cost you a lot of money.
Now what about this,
the famous blue cheese?
We didn't mention
it, but this is a very
famous French cheese
that basically has mold on it.
Well, yeah, all cheese,
you're growing cultures,
you're growing these
things that are alive.
But blue cheese, you
can actually see it and it's
moldy, it's white and there's
some blue or green mold.
Exactly.
So I love it and
some people hate it, it
depends on your tastes, but it
does have a very strong flavor.
Well, do you personally
like it or do I do
not like blue cheese,
but I love other kinds
of cheeses like Camembert,
which is a French
cheese with a very strong
flavor, very stinky cheese.
So it's not necessarily
that it's strong, it's
just that I don't like
the taste very much.
Okay.
Actually, it's very
popular to put on salads,
right, blue cheese sauce or a
dressing, blue cheese dressing?
Yeah, that's right.
It's made out of blue cheese.
It's a very interesting
topic and I'm sure
that locally many people also make or
countries have their own types of cheese.
I know, for example, in Ecuador, we do have
also something very similar to Kesso Frisco
and that's commonly used for
breakfast and here's an interesting thing.
They put it in their cup of coffee.
No way.
So it's cheese cheese, isn't it?
It's cheese, so basically
you have coffee with
milk, very popular in
Latin America and people
will take a piece of cheese
and put it in their coffee.
So obviously with
the heat, it won't melt
completely, but it will
become very bendy and
very soft and then they'll have
it with the coffee and the bread.
So it gives it a very interesting taste.
It may sound a little
bit peculiar, but it
actually has a very,
very interesting taste.
Very good taste.
I've had many friends try and they're like,
wow, you wouldn't really think that you
would probably dip cheese
in coffee, but it works.
No, it's a very unusual combination.
Now, what is a special cheese called?
It's also, it's called
Gesso Limissa, which
is basically a normal,
common, everyday table cheese.
So it's not any particular, it's very similar
to Kesso Frisco, very immature cheese.
So I'm very curious to know if in your
country you also have a strong cheese culture
and if in your country you guys do have
a lot of cheese, what kind of cheese is it?
I know that every
country has its own, the
variety of cheeses and some places
like China aren't really into cheese.
So you can let us know if your country
doesn't really have that many cheese options.
So very curious to hear about
you and your taste and cheese.
Let us know.
Our website is www.englishpod.com.
We hope to see you there.
All right, guys.
See you later.
Bye.
[BLANK_AUDIO]